phpsugar.com 2018-01-16

# Privacy Policy - PHP Melody

### Collected Data

While accessing our website(s) we collect anonymous data from each visitor because that allows us to provide uninterrupted services. Usually we, or the 3rd party services we work with, use cookies to track our website traffic.

When ordering or logging into accounts such as our blog, forums or the 'Customer Area' we store and track data such as IP addresses, timestamp and other identifiers which you choose share with us.

Any information collected from our orders is used exclusively for order processing, notifications and product delivery. We don't collect any information about your credit card because we do not process any of the payments on our server. Payments are processed by 3rd party payment processors such as: Avangate.com, FastSpring.com, Regnow.com, Emetrix.com, PayPal.com and/or Moneybookers.com.

All the data resulted from your order with us is never shared with anyone outside our company in any way, shape or form. Never. This also applies to data we collect for our newsletter.

### Cookies

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser, and stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

Cookies can be used by web servers to identity and track users as they navigate different pages on a website and to identify users returning to a website. 

Cookies do not contain any information that personally identifies you, but personal information that we store about you may be linked, by us, to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

For example, browser cookies are used to store certain login details in order to speed up future logins. You can choose to turn off cookies by adjusting your browser's settings accordingly.

We operate an "implied consent" policy which means that we assume you agree with this usage.

### Data Security

We will take reasonable technical and organizational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information. Collected data is safely stored on our leased server(s) and is behind a firewall protection and managed by professionals in server-security.

You are responsible for keeping your password and other login details confidential. We never ask for your password, excepting of course the login forms from our website(s).

### Use of Collected Data

Data such as name, email address which you provide during the order process is only used in special circumstances such as customer support and other direct communications between us and yourself.

Other data collected during your browsing sessions and account logins may be used to:

  1. provide customer support;
  2. facilitate uninterrupted use of the customer-only services;
  3. improve the website experience;
  4. generate statistics on website usage;
  5. prevent hacking attempts on your accounts with us;
  6. send invoices;
  7. notify license holders relating to their license;
  8. send general notifications about the product (non-marketing; you can opt-out of this program);
  9. verify compliance with the terms and conditions governing the use of our products, services and website.

We do not share personal information you have provided to us.

We may contact your regarding promotional offers we believe you might be interested in at a rate of one email per month. If you don't want to receive such alerts, you can easily unsubscribe at any time.

### 3rd party Services

We don't share your personal information with anyone. The following services we use to run our business receive at best only anonym data from your browsing session. We currently use the following 3rd party services: Google Analytics (traffic analysis and optimization) and MailChimp (mailing list management).

Data sent to Google Analytics is anonymous and includes browser type, location, language settings, page views, time/date. With MailChimp we only use your email address (only if you joined any of our newsletters).

### Your Rights

You can request to have any stored data about your removed from our servers. This usually accompanies the termination of any contract between us and you. We remove all removable data both from our server(s) and the 3rd party services we use.

### Final Note

We reserve the right to modify or append our privacy policy at any future date. If you have any questions or concerns, please contact our team.
